<?xml version="1.0"?>
<collection genre="Romantic Comedy" release="1977,1978" country="USA" >
	<film>
		<title>Annie Hall</title>
		<released>1977-09-29</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Allen, Woody">Woody Allen</name>
		</director>
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<genre>Romantic Comedy, Drama, Comedy</genre>
		<country>USA</country>
		<image>anniehall.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Annie_Hall" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Annie Hall is a 1977 American romantic comedy film directed by <writer>
					<name sort="Allen, Woody">Woody Allen</name>
				</writer> from a screenplay he co-wrote with <writer>
					<name sort="Brickman, Marshall">Marshall Brickman</name>
				</writer>. Produced by Allen's manager,  <producer>
					<name sort=" Joffe, Charles H.">Charles H. Joffe</name>
				</producer>, the film stars the director as Alvy "Max" Singer, who tries to figure out the reasons for the failure of his relationship with the film's eponymous female lead, played by <actor><name sort="Keaton, Diane">Diane Keaton</name></actor> in a role written specifically for her.</p>
			<p>Principal photography for the film began on May 19, 1976 on the South Fork of Long Island, and filming continued periodically for the next ten months. Allen has described the result, which marked his first collaboration with cinematographer Gordon Willis, as "a major turning point", in that unlike the farces and comedies that were his work to that point, it introduced a new level of seriousness. Academics have noted the contrast in the settings of New York City and Los Angeles, the stereotype of gender differences in sexuality, the presentation of Jewish identity, and the elements of psychoanalysis and modernism.</p>
			<p>Annie Hall was screened at the Los Angeles Film Festival in March 1977, before its official release on April 20, 1977. The film received widespread critical acclaim, and along with winning the Academy Award for Best Picture, it received Oscars in three other categories: two for Allen (Best Director and, with Brickman, Best Original Screenplay), and Keaton for Best Actress. The film additionally won four BAFTA awards and a Golden Globe, the latter being awarded to Keaton. Its North American box office receipts of $38,251,425 are fourth-best in the director's oeuvre when not adjusted for inflation. Often listed among the greatest film comedies, it ranks 31st on AFI's list of the top feature films in American cinema, fourth on their list of top comedy films and number 28 on Bravo's "100 Funniest Movies." Film critic Roger Ebert called it "just about everyone's favorite Woody Allen movie". The film has been named the funniest screenplay by the Writers Guild of America in its list of the "101 Funniest Screenplays."</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Brazil</title>
		<released>1985-02-22</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Gilliam, Terry">Terry Gilliam</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Milchan, Arnon">Arnon Milchan</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<genre>Science fiction</genre>
		<country>UK</country>		
		<image>brazil.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brazil_(1985_film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Brazil is a 1985 dystopian science fiction film directed by Terry Gilliam and written by <writer><name sort="Gillam, Terry">Gilliam</name></writer>, <writer><name sort="McKeown, Charles">Charles McKeown</name></writer>, and <writer><name sort="Stoppard, Tom">Tom Stoppard</name></writer>. The film stars <actor><name sort="Pryce, Jonathan">Jonathan Pryce</name></actor> and features <actor><name sort="De Niro, Robert">Robert De Niro</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Greist, Kim">Kim Greist</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Palin, Michael">Michael Palin</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Helmond, Katherine">Katherine Helmond</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Hoskins, Bob">Bob Hoskins</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Holm, Ian">Ian Holm</name></actor>.</p>
			<p>The film centres on Sam Lowry, a man trying to find a woman who appears in his dreams while he is working in a mind-numbing job and living a life in a small apartment, set in a consumer-driven dystopian world in which there is an over-reliance on poorly maintained (and rather whimsical) machines. Brazil's bureaucratic, totalitarian government is reminiscent of the government depicted in George Orwell's Nineteen Eighty-Four, except that it has a buffoonish, slapstick quality and lacks a Big Brother figure.</p>
			<p>Jack Mathews, film critic and author of The Battle of Brazil (1987), described the film as "satirizing the bureaucratic, largely dysfunctional industrial world that had been driving Gilliam crazy all his life". Though a success in Europe, the film was unsuccessful in its initial North America release. It has since become a cult film. In Brazil, some local movie critics believe it intended to make a satirical portrait on the Brazilian military government which was about to end on its release date.</p>
			<p>The film is named after the recurrent theme song, Ary Barroso's "Aquarela do Brasil", as performed by Geoff Muldaur.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Citizen Kane</title>
		<released>1941-05-01</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Welles, Orson">Orson Welles</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Welles, Orson">Orson Welles</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<genre>Drama, Film Noir</genre>
		<country>USA</country>
		<image>citizenkane.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citizen_Kane" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Citizen Kane is a 1941 American drama film by Orson Welles, its producer, co-author, director and star. The picture was Welles's first feature film. Nominated for Academy Awards in nine categories, it won an Academy Award for Best Writing (Original Screenplay) by <writer><name sort="Mankiewicz, Herman J.">Herman J. Mankiewicz</name></writer> and <writer><name sort="Welles, Orson">Welles</name></writer>. Considered by many critics, filmmakers, and fans to be the greatest film ever made, Citizen Kane was voted the greatest film of all time in five consecutive Sight and Sound polls of critics, until it was displaced by Vertigo in the 2012 poll. It topped the American Film Institute's 100 Years ... 100 Movies list in 1998, as well as AFI's 2007 update. Citizen Kane is particularly praised for its cinematography, music, and narrative structure, which were innovative for its time.</p>
			<p>The story is a film that examines the life and legacy of Charles Foster Kane, played by <actor><name sort="Welles, Orson">Orson Welles</name></actor>, a character based in part upon the American newspaper magnate William Randolph Hearst, Chicago tycoons Samuel Insull and Harold McCormick, and aspects of Welles's own life. Upon its release, Hearst prohibited mention of the film in any of his newspapers. Kane's career in the publishing world is born of idealistic social service, but gradually evolves into a ruthless pursuit of power. Narrated principally through flashbacks, the story is told through the research of a newsreel reporter seeking to solve the mystery of the newspaper magnate's dying word: "Rosebud".</p>
			<p>After the Broadway successes of Welles's Mercury Theatre and the controversial 1938 radio broadcast "The War of the Worlds" on The Mercury Theatre on the Air, Welles was courted by Hollywood. He signed a contract with RKO Pictures in 1939. Unusual for an untried director, he was given the freedom to develop his own story, to use his own cast and crew, and to have final cut privilege. Following two abortive attempts to get a project off the ground, he wrote the screenplay for Citizen Kane, collaborating on the effort with Herman Mankiewicz. Principal photography took place in 1940 and the film received its American release in 1941.</p>
			<p>While a critical success, Citizen Kane failed to recoup its costs at the box office. The film faded from view after its release but was subsequently returned to the public's attention when it was praised by such French critics as Andre Bazin and given an American revival in 1956. The film was released on Blu-ray Disc on September 13, 2011, for a special 70th anniversary edition.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb</title>
		<released>1964-01-29</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Kubrick, Stanley">Stanley Kubrick</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Kubrick, Stanley">Stanley Kubrick</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Black Comedy, Political Satire, Science Fiction</genre>
		<image>drstrangelove.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dr._Strangelove" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb, more commonly known as Dr. Strangelove, is a 1964 political satire black comedy film that satirizes the Cold War fears of a nuclear conflict between the USSR and the US. The film was directed, produced, and co-written by <writer><name sort="Kubrick, Stanley">Stanley Kubrick</name></writer>, stars <actor><name sort="Sellers, Peter">Peter Sellers</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Scott, George C.">George C. Scott</name></actor>, and features <actor><name sort="Hayden, Sterling">Sterling Hayden</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Wynn, Keenan">Keenan Wynn</name></actor>, and <actor><name sort="Pickens, Slim">Slim Pickens</name></actor>. Production took place in the United Kingdom. The film is loosely based on Peter George's thriller novel Red Alert.</p>
			<p>The story concerns an unhinged United States Air Force general who orders a first strike nuclear attack on the Soviet Union. It follows the President of the United States, his advisers, the Joint Chiefs of Staff, and a Royal Air Force (RAF) officer as they try to recall the bombers to prevent a nuclear apocalypse. It separately follows the crew of one B-52 bomber as they try to deliver their payload.</p>
			<p>In 1989, the United States Library of Congress included it in the first group of films selected for preservation in the National Film Registry. It was listed as number three on AFI's 100 Years...100 Laughs list.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Ed Wood</title>
		<released>1994-09-30</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Burton, Tim">Tim Burton</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Burton, Tim">Tim Burton</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Di Novi, Denise">Denise Di Novi</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Biography, Comedy, Drama</genre>
		<image>edwood.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ed_Wood_(film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Ed Wood is a 1994 American period comedy-drama biopic directed and produced by Tim Burton, and starring <actor><name sort="Depp, Johnny">Johnny Depp</name></actor> as cult filmmaker Ed Wood. The film concerns the period in Wood's life when he made his best-known films as well as his relationship with actor Bela Lugosi, played by <actor><name sort="Landau, Martin">Martin Landau</name></actor>. <actor><name sort="Parker, Sarah Jessica">Sarah Jessica Parker</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Arquette, Patricia">Patricia Arquette</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Jones, Jeffrey">Jeffrey Jones</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Marie, Lisa">Lisa Marie</name></actor>, and <actor><name sort="Murray, Bill">Bill Murray</name></actor> are among the supporting cast.</p>
			<p>The film was conceived by writers <writer><name sort="Alexander, Scott">Scott Alexander</name></writer> and <writer><name sort="Karaszewski, Larry">Larry Karaszewski</name></writer> when they were students at the USC School of Cinematic Arts. Irritated at being thought of solely as writers for family films with their work on Problem Child and its sequel, Alexander and Karaszewski struck a deal with Burton and Denise Di Novi to produce the Ed Wood biopic, and Michael Lehmann as director. Due to scheduling conflicts with Airheads, Lehmann had to vacate the director's position, which was taken over by Burton.</p>
			<p>Ed Wood was originally in development at Columbia Pictures, but the studio put the film in 'turnaround' over Burton's decision to shoot in black-and-white. Ed Wood was taken to the Walt Disney Studios, which produced the film through the studio's Touchstone Pictures division. The film was released to huge critical acclaim, but it would prove to be a box office disappointment, making only $5.9 million against an $18 million budget. It won two Academy Awards: Best Supporting Actor for Landau and Best Makeup for Rick Baker (who designed Landau's prosthetic makeup), Ve Neill and Yolanda Toussieng.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>A Fish Called Wanda</title>
		<released>1988-07-15</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Crichton, Charles">Charles Crichton</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Shamberg, Michael">Michael Shamberg</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>UK</country>
		<genre>Comedy</genre>
		<image>afishcalledwanda.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/A_Fish_Called_Wanda" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>A Fish Called Wanda is a 1988 heist-comedy film written by <writer><name sort="Cleese, John">John Cleese</name></writer> and <writer><name sort="Crichton, Charles">Charles Crichton</name></writer>. It was directed by Crichton (it was his final film) and stars <actor><name sort="Cleese, John">Cleese</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Curtis, Jamie Lee">Jamie Lee Curtis</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Kline, Kevin">Kevin Kline</name></actor>, and <actor><name sort="Palin, Michael">Michael Palin</name></actor>. Kline won the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actor for his performance as Otto. Cleese and Palin won BAFTA Awards for Best Lead and Best Supporting for their acting.</p>
			<p>The plot involves members of the crew of a successful diamond heist as they manipulate and double-cross one-another in an effort to find the diamonds, which have been hidden by the gang's leader just before he was arrested, having been set-up by one of his subordinates. His barrister, played by Cleese, becomes a central figure in the crew's schemes as femme fatale Wanda (Curtis) uses him to locate the loot.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>The Godfather</title>
		<released>1972-05-24</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Ford Coppola, Francis">Francis Ford Coppola</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Ruddy, Albert S.">Ruddy, Albert S.</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>R18+</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Crime, Drama</genre>
		<image>thegodfather.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Godfather" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>The Godfather is a 1972 American crime film directed by Francis Ford Coppola and produced by Albert S. Ruddy from a screenplay by <writer><name sort="Puzo, Mario">Mario Puzo</name></writer> and <writer><name sort="Coppola, Francis Ford">Coppola</name></writer>. Starring <actor><name sort="Brando, Marlon">Marlon Brando</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Pacino, Al">Al Pacino</name></actor> as the leaders of the fictional Corleone New York crime family, the story spans the years 1945-55, concentrating on the transformation of Michael Corleone from reluctant family outsider to ruthless Mafia boss while chronicling the family under the patriarch Vito.</p>
			<p>Based on Puzo's best-selling novel of the same name, The Godfather is widely regarded as one of the greatest films in world cinema and as one of the most influential, especially in the gangster genre. Ranked second to Citizen Kane by the American Film Institute in 2007, it was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry of the Library of Congress in 1990 as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".</p>
			<p>The film was the box office leader for 1972 and was, for a time, the highest-grossing picture ever made. It won three Academy Awards for that year: Best Picture, Best Actor (Brando) and in the category Best Adapted Screenplay for Puzo and Coppola. Its nominations in seven other categories included Pacino, <actor><name sort="Caan, James">James Caan</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Duvall, Robert">Robert Duvall</name></actor> for Best Supporting Actor and Coppola for Best Director. The success spawned two sequels: The Godfather Part II in 1974, and The Godfather Part III in 1990.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Harold and Maude</title>
		<released>1971-12-20</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Ashby, Hal">Hal Ashby</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Higgins, Colin">Colin Higgins</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Mulvehill, Charles B.">Charles B. Mulvehill</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Romantic Comedy, Dark Commedy, Existentialist Drama</genre>
		<image>haroldandmaude.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Harold_and_Maude" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Harold and Maude is a 1971 American romantic dark comedy directed by Hal Ashby and released by Paramount Pictures. It incorporates elements of dark humor and existentialist drama, with a plot that revolves around the exploits of a young man named Harold (played by <actor><name sort="Cort, Bud">Bud Cort</name></actor>) intrigued with death. Harold drifts away from the life that his detached mother (<actor><name sort="Pickles, Vivian">Vivian Pickles</name></actor>) prescribes for him, and slowly develops quite a strong and close friendship and eventually a romantic relationship with a 79-year-old woman named Maude (<actor><name sort="Gordon, Ruth">Ruth Gordon</name></actor>) who teaches Harold about living life to its fullest and that life is the most precious gift of all.</p>
			<p>The film was based on a screenplay written by <writer><name sort="Higgins, Colin">Colin Higgins</name></writer> and published as a novel in 1971. Filming locations in the San Francisco Bay Area included both Holy Cross Cemetery and Golden Gate National Cemetery, and the ruins of the Sutro Baths.</p>
			<p>Critically and commercially unsuccessful when originally released, the film developed a cult following and in 1983 began making a profit. The film is ranked number 45 on the American Film Institute's list of 100 Funniest Movies of all Time and was selected for preservation in the National Film Registry of the Library of Congress in 1997, for being "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant".[3] The Criterion Collection special edition Blu-ray and DVD were released June 12, 2012.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade</title>
		<released>1989-05-24</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Spielberg, Steven">Steven Spielberg</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Watts, Robert">Robert Watts</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Lucas, George">George Lucas</name>
		</producer>		
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Action, Adventure</genre>
		<image>indianajones.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Indiana_Jones_and_the_Last_Crusade" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Indiana Jones and the Last Crusade is a 1989 American action-adventure film directed by Steven Spielberg, from a story co-written by executive producer <writer><name sort="Lucas, George">George Lucas</name></writer>. It is the third installment in the Indiana Jones franchise. <actor><name sort="Ford, Harrison">Harrison Ford</name></actor> reprises the title role and <actor><name sort="Connery, Sean">Sean Connery</name></actor> plays Indiana's father, Henry Jones, Sr. Other cast members featured include <actor><name sort="Doody, Alison">Alison Doody</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Elliot, Denholm">Denholm Elliott</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Glover, Julian">Julian Glover</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Phoenix, River">River Phoenix</name></actor>, and <actor><name sort="Rhys-Davies, John">John Rhys-Davies</name></actor>. In the film, set largely in 1938, Indiana searches for his father, a Holy Grail scholar, who has been kidnapped by Nazis.</p>
			<p>After the mixed reaction to Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom, Spielberg chose to compensate with a film that toned down the violence and gore. During the five years between Temple of Doom and Last Crusade, he and executive producer Lucas reviewed several scripts before accepting <writer><name sort="Boam, Jeffrey">Jeffrey Boam</name></writer>'s. Filming locations included Spain, Italy, the United Kingdom, Turkey and Jordan.</p>
			<p>The film was released in North America on May 24, 1989 to mostly positive reviews. It was a financial success, earning $474,171,806 at the worldwide box office totals. It won an Academy Award for Best Sound Editing.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Jaws</title>
		<released>1975-06-20</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Spielberg, Steven">Steven Spielberg</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Zanuck, Richard D.">Richard D. Zanuck</name>
		</producer>	
		<director>
			<name sort="Brown, David">David Brown</name>
		</director>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Adventure, Horror, Thriller</genre>
		<image>jaws.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jaws_(film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Jaws is a 1975 American film directed by Steven Spielberg and based on <writer><name sort="Benchley, Peter">Peter Benchley</name></writer>'s 1974 novel Jaws. The prototypical summer blockbuster, its release is regarded as a watershed moment in motion picture history. In the story, a giant man-eating great white shark attacks beachgoers on Amity Island, a fictional New England summer resort town, prompting the local police chief to hunt it with the help of a marine biologist and a professional shark hunter. The film stars <actor><name sort="Scheider, Roy">Roy Scheider</name></actor> as police chief Martin Brody, <actor><name sort="Dreyfuss, Richard">Richard Dreyfuss</name></actor> as oceanographer Matt Hooper, <actor><name sort="Shaw, Robert">Robert Shaw</name></actor> as shark hunter Quint, <actor><name sort="Hamilton, Murray">Murray Hamilton</name></actor> as Larry Vaughn, the mayor of Amity Island, and <actor><name sort="Gary, Lorraine">Lorraine Gary</name></actor> as Brody's wife, Ellen. The screenplay is credited to both Benchley, who wrote the first drafts, and actor-writer <writer><name sort="Gottlieb, Carl">Carl Gottlieb</name></writer>, who rewrote the script during principal photography.</p>
			<p>Shot mostly on location on Martha's Vineyard in Massachusetts, the film had a troubled production, going over budget and past schedule. As the art department's mechanical sharks suffered many malfunctions, Spielberg decided to mostly suggest the animal's presence, employing an ominous, minimalistic theme created by composer John Williams to indicate the shark's impending appearances. Spielberg and others have compared this suggestive approach to that of classic thriller director Alfred Hitchcock. Universal Pictures gave the film what was then an exceptionally wide release for a major studio picture, over 450 screens, accompanied by an extensive marketing campaign with a heavy emphasis on television spots and tie-in merchandise.</p>
			<p>Generally well received by critics, Jaws became the highest-grossing film of all time until Star Wars. It won several awards for its soundtrack and editing. Along with Star Wars, Jaws was pivotal in establishing the modern Hollywood business model, which revolves around high box-office returns from action and adventure pictures with simple "high-concept" premises that are released during the summer in thousands of theaters and supported by heavy advertising. It was followed by three sequels, none with the participation of Spielberg or Benchley, and many imitative thrillers. In 2001, Jaws was selected by the Library of Congress for preservation in the United States National Film Registry, being deemed "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant".</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>King Kong</title>
		<released>1933-03-02</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Cooper, Merian C.">Merian C. Cooper</name>
			<name sort="Schoedsack, Ernest B.">Ernest B. Schoedsack</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Cooper, Merian C.">Merian C. Cooper</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Schoedsack, Ernest B.">Ernest B. Schoedsack</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Selznick, David O.">David O. Selznick</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Drama, Romance</genre>
		<image>kingkong.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/King_Kong_(1933_film)" title="Wikipedia page"/>
		<summary>
			<p>King Kong is a 1933 American Pre-Code fantasy monster/adventure film directed and produced by Merian C. Cooper and Ernest B. Schoedsack. The screenplay by
				<writer><name sort="Creelman, James Ashmore">James Ashmore Creelman</name></writer>
				and <writer><name sort="Rose, Ruth">Ruth Rose</name></writer> was from an idea conceived by Cooper and Edgar Wallace. It stars <actor><name sort="Wray, Fay">Fay Wray</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Cabot, Bruce">Bruce Cabot</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Armstrong, Robert">Robert Armstrong</name></actor>, and opened in New York City on March 2, 1933 to rave reviews. It has been ranked by movie site Rotten Tomatoes as Greatest horror film of all time. </p>
			<p>The film tells of a gigantic, prehistoric, island-dwelling ape called Kong who dies in an attempt to possess a beautiful young woman. King Kong is especially noted for its stop-motion animation by Willis O'Brien and a groundbreaking musical score by Max Steiner. In 1991, it was deemed "culturally, historically and aesthetically significant" by the Library of Congress and selected for preservation in the National Film Registry. It has been remade twice: in 1976 and in 2005.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Life Is Beautiful</title>
		<released>1998-10-23</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Benigni, Roberto">Roberto Benigni</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Braschi, Gianluigi">Gianluigi Braschi</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Ferri, Elda">Elda Ferri</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>Italy</country>
		<genre>Tragi Comedy, Drama, Romance</genre>
		<image>lifeisbeautiful.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Life_Is_Beautiful" title="Wikipedia page"/>
		<summary>
			<p>Life Is Beautiful is a 1997 Italian tragicomic comedy-drama film directed by and starring <writer><name sort="Benigini, Roberto">Roberto Benigni</name></writer>, who co-wrote the film with <writer><name sort="Cerami, Vincenzo">Vincenzo Cerami</name></writer>. <actor><name sort="Benigin, Roberto">Benigni</name></actor> plays Guido Orefice, a Jewish Italian book shop owner, who must employ his fertile imagination to shield his son from the horrors of internment in a Nazi concentration camp. Part of the film came from Benigni's own family history; before Roberto's birth, his father had survived three years of internment at the Bergen-Belsen concentration camp.</p>
			<p>The film was a critical and financial success, winning Benigni the Academy Award for Best Actor at the 71st Academy Awards as well as the Academy Award for Best Original Dramatic Score and the Academy Award for Best Foreign Language Film.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Miller's Crossing</title>
		<released>1990-09-21</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Coen, Joel">Joel Coen</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Coen, Ethan">Ethan Coen</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Crime, Drama, Thriller</genre>
		<image>millerscrossing.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miller's_Crossing" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Miller's Crossing is a 1990 American neo-noir black comedy gangster film written and directed by the Coen brothers, and starring <actor><name sort="Byrne, Gabriel">Gabriel Byrne</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Harden, Marcia Gay">Marcia Gay Harden</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Turturro, John">John Turturro</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Polito, Jon">Jon Polito</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Freeman J. E.">J. E. Freeman</name></actor>, and <actor><name sort="Finney, Albert">Albert Finney</name></actor>. The plot concerns a power struggle between two rival gangs and how the protagonist, Tom Regan[1] (Gabriel Byrne), plays both sides off against each other.</p>
			<p>In 2005, TIME chose Miller's Crossing as one of the 100 greatest films made since the inception of the periodical. TIME critic Richard Corliss called it a "noir with a touch so light, the film seems to float on the breeze like the frisbee of a fedora sailing through the forest."</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Nashville</title>
		<released>1975-06-11</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Atman, Robert">Robert Altman</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Altman, Robert">Robert Altman</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Weintraub, Jerry">Jerry Weintraub</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Comedy, Drama, Musical</genre>
		<image>nashville.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nashville_(film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Nashville is a 1975 American musical drama film directed by Robert Altman. A winner of numerous awards and selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry, Nashville is generally considered to be one of Altman's best films.</p>
			<p>The film takes a snapshot of people involved in the country music and gospel music businesses in Nashville, Tennessee. It has 24 main characters, an hour of musical numbers, and multiple storylines. The characters' efforts to succeed or hold on to their success are interwoven with the efforts of a political operative and a local businessman to stage a concert rally before the state's presidential primary for a populist outsider running for President of the United States on the Replacement Party ticket. In the film's final half-hour, most of the characters come together at the outdoor concert at the Parthenon in Nashville.</p>
			<p>The large ensemble cast includes <actor><name sort="Arkin, David">David Arkin</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Baxley, Barbara">Barbara Baxley</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Beatty, Ned">Ned Beatty</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Black, Karen">Karen Black</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Blakley, Ronee">Ronee Blakley</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Brown, Timothy">Timothy Brown</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Caradine, Keith">Keith Carradine</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Chaplin, Geraldine">Geraldine Chaplin</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="DoQui, Robert">Robert DoQui</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Duvall, Shelley">Shelley Duvall</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Garfield, Allen">Allen Garfield</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Gibson, Henry">Henry Gibson</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Glenn, Scott">Scott Glenn</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Goldblum, Jeff">Jeff Goldblum</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Harris, Barbara">Barbara Harris</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Hayward, David">David Hayward</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Murphy, Michael">Michael Murphy</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Nicholls, Allan F.">Allan F. Nicholls</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Peel, Dave">Dave Peel</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Raines, Cristina">Cristina Raines</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Remsen, Bert">Bert Remsen</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Tomlin, Lily">Lily Tomlin</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Welles, Gwen">Gwen Welles</name></actor>, and <actor><name sort="Wynn, Keenan">Keenan Wynn</name></actor>.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>On the Waterfront</title>		
		<released>1954-07-28</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Kazan, Elia">Elia Kazan</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Spiegel, Sam">Sam Spiegel</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Drama, Thriller</genre>
		<image>onthewaterfront.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/On_the_Waterfront" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>On the Waterfront is a 1954 American crime drama film with elements of film noir. The film was directed by Elia Kazan and written by <writer><name sort="Schulberg, Budd">Budd Schulberg</name></writer>. It stars <actor><name sort="Brando, Marlon">Marlon Brando</name></actor> and features <actor><name sort="Malden, Karl">Karl Malden</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Cobb, Lee J.">Lee J. Cobb</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Steiger, Rod">Rod Steiger</name></actor>, and, in her film debut, <actor><name sort="Saint, Eva Marie">Eva Marie Saint</name></actor>. The soundtrack score was composed by Leonard Bernstein. It is based on Crime on the Waterfront, a series of articles published in the New York Sun by Malcolm Johnson that won the 1949 Pulitzer Prize for Local Reporting. The film focuses on union violence and corruption amongst longshoremen while detailing widespread corruption, extortion, and racketeering on the waterfronts of Hoboken, New Jersey.</p>
			<p>On the Waterfront was a critical and commercial success and received 12 Academy Award nominations, winning eight, including Best Picture, Best Actor for Brando, Best Supporting Actress for Saint, and Best Director for Kazan. In 1997 it was ranked by the American Film Institute as the eighth-greatest American movie of all time and in AFI's 2007 list it was ranked 19th. It is Bernstein's only original film score not adapted from a stage production with songs.</p>
			<p>In 1989, On the Waterfront was deemed "culturally, historically or aesthetically significant" by the Library of Congress and selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>The Princess Bride</title>
		<released>1987-09-25</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Reiner, Rob">Rob Reiner</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Reiner, Rob">Rob Reiner</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Scheinman, Andrew">Andrew Scheinman</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Action, Adventure, Comedy, Romance</genre>
		<image>theprincessbride.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Princess_Bride_(film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>The Princess Bride is a 1987 American fantasy comedy adventure film directed and co-produced by Rob Reiner, and starring <actor><name sort="Elwes, Cary">Cary Elwes</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Wright, Robin">Robin Wright</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Patinkin, Mandy">Mandy Patinkin</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Sarandon, Chris">Chris Sarandon</name></actor>, and <actor><name sort="Guest, Christopher">Christopher Guest</name></actor>. Adapted by <writer><name sort="Goldman, William">William Goldman</name></writer> from his 1973 novel of the same name, it tells the story about a farmhand named Westley, accompanied by befriended companions along the way, who must rescue his true love Princess Buttercup from the odious Prince Humperdinck. The story is presented in the film as a book being read by a grandfather (<actor><name sort="Falk, Peter">Peter Falk</name></actor>) to his sick grandson (<actor><name sort="Savage, Fred">Fred Savage</name></actor>), thus effectively preserving the novel's narrative style.</p>
			<p>Released in the United States on September 25, 1987, the film initially achieved moderate success at the box office. Despite being a moderate success, the film received critical acclaim from film critics. Since its release, the film was successful in the home video market and later developed a much more substantial following as a cult classic.[1] This film is number 50 on Bravo's "100 Funniest Movies", number 88 on The American Film Institute's (AFI) "AFI's 100 Years...100 Passions" list of the 100 greatest film love stories, and 46 in Channel 4's 50 Greatest Comedy Films list.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>The Quick and the Dead</title>
		<released>1995-02-10</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Raimi, Sam">Sam Raimi</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Donen, Joshua">Joshua Donen</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Markey, Patrick">Patrick Markey</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Shapiro, Allen">Allen Shapiro</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Action, Drama, Thriller, Western</genre>
		<image>thequickandthedead.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Quick_and_the_Dead_(1995_film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>The Quick and the Dead is a 1995 American western film directed by Sam Raimi, and starring <actor><name sort="Stone, Sharon">Sharon Stone</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Hackman, Gene">Gene Hackman</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Crowe, Russell">Russell Crowe</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="DiCaprio, Leonardo">Leonardo DiCaprio</name></actor>. The story focuses on "The Lady" (Stone), a gunfighter who rides into the frontier town of Redemption, controlled by John Herod (Hackman). The Lady joins a deadly dueling competition in an attempt to exact revenge for her father's death.</p>
			<p><writer><name sort="Moore, Simon">Simon Moore</name></writer>'s script was purchased by Sony Pictures Entertainment in May 1993, and actress Sharon Stone signed on as both star and co-producer. Development was fast tracked after director Sam Raimi's hiring, and principal photography began in Old Tucson Studios in Arizona on November 21, 1993. The film was distributed by TriStar Pictures and Columbia Pictures, and was released in the US on February 10, 1995 to a dismal box office performance, receiving lukewarm reviews from critics.</p>
			<p>This was Russell Crowe's first American film debut. This was <actor><name sort="Strode, Woody">Woody Strode</name></actor>'s final performance (the film is dedicated to him), as well as the last theatrical release of <actor><name sort="Blossom, Roberts">Roberts Blossom</name></actor> who died in 2011. The phrase "the quick and the dead" is from the Book of Common Prayer and its version of the Apostles' Creed, describing the final judgement. The plot of this film bears no resemblance to that of the 1987 film of the same name, which was based on a western novel by Louis L'Amour.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Raging Bull</title>
		<released>1980-12-19</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Scorsese, Martin">Martin Scorsese</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Winkler, Irwin">Irwin Winkler</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Chartoff, Robert">Robert Chartoff</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>R18+</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Biography, Drama</genre>
		<image>ragingbull.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raging_Bull" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Raging Bull is a 1980 American biographical black-and-white sports drama film directed by Martin Scorsese, produced by Robert Chartoff and Irwin Winkler and adapted by <writer><name sort="Schrader, Paul">Paul Schrader</name></writer> and <writer><name sort="Martin, Mardik">Mardik Martin</name></writer> from Jake LaMotta's memoir Raging Bull: My Story. It stars <actor><name sort="De Niro, Robert">Robert De Niro</name></actor> as Jake LaMotta, an Italian American middleweight boxer whose self-destructive and obsessive rage, sexual jealousy, and animalistic appetite destroyed his relationship with his wife and family. Also featured in the film are <actor><name sort="Pesci, Joey">Joe Pesci</name></actor> as Joey, La Motta's well-intentioned brother and manager who tries to help Jake battle his inner demons, and <actor><name sort="Moriarty, Cathy">Cathy Moriarty</name></actor> as his wife. The film features supporting roles from <actor><name sort="Colasanto, Nicholas">Nicholas Colasanto</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Saldana, Theresa">Theresa Saldana</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Vincent, Frank">Frank Vincent</name></actor>.</p>
			<p>Scorsese was initially reluctant to develop the project, though he eventually came to relate to La Motta's story. Schrader re-wrote Martin's first screenplay, and Scorsese and De Niro together made uncredited contributions thereafter. Pesci was an unknown actor prior to the film, as was Moriarty, who was suggested for her role by Pesci. During principal photography, each of the boxing scenes was choreographed for a specific visual style and De Niro gained approximately 60 pounds (27 kg) to portray La Motta in his later post-boxing years. Scorsese was exacting in the process of editing and mixing the film, expecting it to be his last major feature[citation needed].</p>
			<p>After receiving mixed initial reviews (and criticism due to its violent content), it went on to garner a high critical reputation and is now regarded among the greatest American films ever made, including by Roger Ebert of the Chicago Sun-Times, Gene Siskel of the Chicago Tribune, British film historian Leslie Halliwell, the American Film Institute, Time, The New York Times, Variety, Entertainment Weekly, Empire, Total Film, Film 4, and BFI's Sight and Sound. It was listed in the National Film Registry in 1990, its first year of eligibility. Raging Bull is voted by many critics including Roger Ebert and Gene Siskel as the best film of the 1980s. The film is now regarded by many to be Scorsese's magnum opus.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Solaris</title>
		<released>1972-03-20</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Tarkovsky, Andrei">Andrei Tarkovsky</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Tarasov, Viacheslav">Viacheslav Tarasov</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>USSR</country>
		<genre>Drama, Mystery, Romance, Science Fiction</genre>
		<image>solaris.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Solaris_(1972_film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Solaris (Russian: ???????, tr. Solyaris) is a 1972 Russian science fiction art film adaptation of Polish author Stanislaw Lem's novel Solaris (1961). The film was co-written and directed by <writer><name sort="Tarkovsky, Andrei">Andrei Tarkovsky</name></writer>.[2][3] The film is a meditative psychological drama occurring mostly aboard a space station orbiting the fictional planet Solaris. The scientific mission has stalled because the skeleton crew of three scientists have fallen into separate emotional crises. Psychologist Kris Kelvin travels to the Solaris space station to evaluate the situation only to encounter the same mysterious phenomena as the others.</p>
			<p>The original science fiction novel is about the ultimate inadequacy of communication between humans and other species. Tarkovsky's adaptation is a "drama of grief and partial recovery" concentrated upon the thoughts and the consciences of the cosmonaut scientists studying Solaris' mysterious ocean.[citation needed] In loyalty to the novel's complex and slow-paced narrative, Tarkovsky wanted to bring a new emotional and intellectual depth to the genre, viewing most of western science fiction as shallow.[4] The ideas which Tarkovsky tried to express in this film are further developed in Stalker (1979).</p>
			<p>The critically successful Solaris features <actor><name sort="Bondarchuk (Hari), Natalya">Natalya Bondarchuk</name></actor> (Hari), <actor><name sort="Banionis, Donatas">Donatas Banionis</name></actor> (Kris Kelvin), <actor><name sort="Jarvet, Juri">Juri Jarvet</name></actor> (Dr Snaut), <actor><name sort="Dvorzhetsky, Vladislav">Vladislav Dvorzhetsky</name></actor> (Henri Berton), <actor><name sort="Grinko, Nikolai">Nikolai Grinko</name></actor> (Kris Kelvin's Father), <actor><name sort="Barnet, Olga">Olga Barnet</name></actor> (Kris Kelvin's Mother), <actor><name sort="Solonitsyn, Anatoli">Anatoli Solonitsyn</name></actor> (Dr Sartorius), and <actor><name sort="Sargsyan, Sos">Sos Sargsyan</name></actor> (Dr Gibarian); the music is by Johann Sebastian Bach and Eduard Artemyev. At the 1972 Cannes Film Festival, it won the Grand Prix Special du Jury, the FIPRESCI prize and was nominated for the Palme d'Or.[6] The film is often cited as one of the greatest science fiction films in the history of cinematography.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>The Truman Show</title>
		<released>1998-06-05</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Weir, Peter">Peter Weir</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Feldman, Edward S.">Edward S. Feldman</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Rudin, Scott">Scott Rudin</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Niccol, Andrew">Andrew Niccol</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Schroeder, Adam">Adam Schroeder</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Comedy, Drama, Science Fiction</genre>
		<image>thetrumanshow.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Truman_Show" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>The Truman Show is a 1998 American science fiction comedy-drama film directed by Peter Weir and written by <writer><name sort="Niccol, Andrew">Andrew Niccol</name></writer>. The film stars <actor><name sort="Carrey, Jim">Jim Carrey</name></actor> as Truman Burbank, <actor><name sort="Linney, Laura">Laura Linney</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Emmerich, Noah">Noah Emmerich</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Harris, Ed">Ed Harris</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="McElhone, Natascha">Natascha McElhone</name></actor>. The film chronicles the life of a man who is initially unaware that he is living in a constructed reality television show, broadcast around the clock to billions of people around the globe. Truman becomes suspicious of his perceived reality and embarks on a quest to discover the truth about his life.</p>
			<p>The genesis of The Truman Show was a spec script by Niccol, inspired by an episode of The Twilight Zone called "Special Service".[1] The original draft was more in tone of a science fiction thriller, with the story set in New York City. Scott Rudin purchased the script, and immediately set the project up at Paramount Pictures. Brian De Palma was in contention to direct before Weir took over and managed to make the film for $60 million against the estimated $80 million budget. Niccol rewrote the script simultaneously as the filmmakers were waiting for Carrey's schedule to open up for filming. The majority of filming took place at Seaside, Florida, a master-planned community located in the Florida Panhandle.</p>
			<p>The film was a financial and critical success, and earned numerous nominations at the 71st Academy Awards, 56th Golden Globe Awards, 52nd British Academy Film Awards and The Saturn Awards. The Truman Show has been analyzed as a thesis on Christianity, metaphilosophy, simulated reality, existentialism and reality television.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Up</title>
		<released>2009-05-29</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Docter, Pete">Pete Docter</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Rivera, Jonas">Jonas Rivera</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>G</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Adventure, Comedy, Drama</genre>
		<image>up.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Up_(2009_film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Up is a 2009 American 3D computer-animated comedy adventure[3] film produced by Pixar and released by Walt Disney Pictures. Directed by Pete Docter, the film centers on an elderly widower named Carl Fredricksen (<actor><name sort="Asner, Edward">Edward Asner</name></actor>) and an earnest young Wilderness Explorer named Russell (<actor><name sort="Nagai, Jordan">Jordan Nagai</name></actor>). By tying thousands of balloons to his home, 78-year-old Carl sets out to fulfill his dream to see the wilds of South America and to complete a promise made to his late wife, Ellie. The film was co-directed by <writer><name sort="Peterson, Bob">Bob Peterson</name></writer>, with music composed by Michael Giacchino.</p>
			<p>Docter began working on the story in 2004, which was based on fantasies of escaping from life when it becomes too irritating. He and eleven other Pixar artists spent three days in Venezuela gathering research and inspiration. The designs of the characters were caricatured and stylized considerably, and animators were challenged with creating realistic cloth. The floating house is attached by a varying number between 10,000 and 20,000 balloons in the film's sequences. Up was Pixar's first film to be presented in Disney Digital 3-D.</p>
			<p>Up was released on May 29, 2009 and opened the 2009 Cannes Film Festival, becoming the first animated and 3D film to do so.[5] The film became a great financial success, accumulating over $731 million in its theatrical release. Up received universal acclaim, with most reviewers commending the humor and heart of the film. Edward Asner was praised for his portrayal of Carl, and a montage of Carl and his wife Ellie aging together was widely lauded. The film received five Academy Award nominations, including Best Picture, making it the second animated film in history to receive such a nomination (and Pixar's first Best Picture nomination), following Beauty and the Beast (1991).[6]</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>Vertigo</title>
		<released>1958-05-09</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Hitchcock, Alfred">Alfred Hitchcock</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Hitchcock, Alfred">Alfred Hitchcock</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Drama, Mystery, Romance, Thriller</genre>
		<image>vertigo.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Vertigo_(film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Vertigo is a 1958 American psychological thriller film directed and produced by Alfred Hitchcock. The story was based on the 1954 novel D'entre les morts (From Among the Dead) by Boileau-Narcejac. The screenplay was written by <writer><name sort="Coppel, Alec">Alec Coppel</name></writer> and <actor><name sort="Taylor, Samuel A.">Samuel A. Taylor</name></actor>.</p>
			<p>The film stars <actor><name sort="Stewart, James">James Stewart</name></actor> as former police detective <actor><name sort="Ferguson, John">John Ferguson</name></actor>. Scottie is forced into early retirement because an incident in the line of duty has caused him to develop acrophobia (an extreme fear of heights) and vertigo (a sensation of false, rotational movement). Scottie is hired by an acquaintance, Gavin Elster, as a private investigator to follow Gavin's wife Madeleine (<actor><name sort="Novak, Kim">Kim Novak</name></actor>), who is behaving strangely.</p>
			<p>The film was shot on location in San Francisco, California, and at Paramount Studios in Hollywood. It is the first film to utilize the dolly zoom, an in-camera effect that distorts perspective to create disorientation, to convey Scottie's acrophobia. As a result of its use in this film, the effect is often referred to as "the Vertigo effect".</p>
			<p>Vertigo received mixed reviews upon initial release, but is now often cited as a classic Hitchcock film and one of the defining works of his career. Attracting significant scholarly criticism, it replaced Citizen Kane (1941) as the best film ever made in the 2012 British Film Institute's Sight and Sound critics' poll.[2] In 1996, the film underwent a major restoration to create a new 70mm print and DTS soundtrack. It has appeared repeatedly in polls of the best films by the American Film Institute,[3] including a 2007 ranking as the ninth-greatest American movie of all time.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>The Wizard of Oz</title>
		<released>1939-08-15</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Fleming, Victor">Victor Fleming</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="LeRoy, Mervyn">Mervyn LeRoy</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>G</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Adventure, Musical</genre>
		<image>thewizardofoz.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wizard_of_Oz_(1939_film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>The Wizard of Oz is a 1939 American musical comedy-drama fantasy film produced by Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer, and the most well-known and commercially successful adaptation based on the 1900 novel The Wonderful Wizard of Oz by L. Frank Baum.[2] The film stars <actor><name sort="Garland, Judy">Judy Garland</name></actor> as Dorothy Gale. The film co-stars Terry the dog, billed as Toto; <actor><name sort="Bolger, Ray">Ray Bolger</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Haley, Jack">Jack Haley</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Lahr, Bert">Bert Lahr</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Morgan, Frank">Frank Morgan</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Burke, Billie">Billie Burke</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Hamilton, Margaret">Margaret Hamilton</name></actor>, with <actor><name sort="Grapewin, Charley">Charley Grapewin</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Blandick, Clara">Clara Blandick</name></actor>, and the Singer Midgets as the Munchkins.</p>
			<p>Notable for its use of Technicolor, fantasy storytelling, musical score and unusual characters, over the years it has become an icon of American popular culture. It was nominated for six Academy Awards, including Best Picture but lost to Gone with the Wind. It did win in two other categories including Best Original Song for "Over the Rainbow". However, the film was a box office disappointment on its initial release, earning only $3,017,000 on a $2,777,000 budget, despite receiving largely positive reviews.[1][4] It was MGM's most expensive production at that time, and did not completely recoup the studio's investment and turn a profit until theatrical re-releases starting in 1949.</p>
			<p>The 1956 broadcast television premiere of the film on CBS re-introduced the film to the wider public and eventually made the presentation an annual tradition, making it one of the most known films in cinema history.[2] The film was named the most-viewed motion picture on television syndication by the Library of Congress who also included the film in its National Film Registry in its inaugural year in 1989. Designation on the registry calls for efforts to preserve it for being "culturally, historically, and aesthetically significant".[6] It is also one of the few films on UNESCO's Memory of the World Register.</p>
			<p>The Wizard of Oz is often ranked on best-movie lists in critics' and public polls. It is the source of many quotes referenced in modern popular culture. It was directed primarily by Victor Fleming (who left production to take over direction on the troubled Gone with the Wind production). <writer><name sort="Langley, Noel">Noel Langley</name></writer>, <writer><name sort="Ryerson, Florence">Florence Ryerson</name></writer> and <writer><name sort="Woolf, Edgar Allan">Edgar Allan Woolf</name></writer> received credit for the screenplay, but there were uncredited contributions by others. The songs were written by Edgar "Yip" Harburg (lyrics) and Harold Arlen (music). The incidental music, based largely on the songs, was composed by Herbert Stothart, with interspersed renderings from classical composers.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>The X-Files</title>
		<released>1998-06-19</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Bowman, Rob">Rob Bowman</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Carter, Chris">Chris Carter</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Sackheim, Daniel">Daniel Sackheim</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>USA</country>
		<genre>Drama, Mystery, Science Fiction, Thriller</genre>
		<image>xfiles.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_X-Files_(film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>The X-Files (also known as The X-Files: Fight the Future) is a 1998 American science fiction film directed by Rob Bowman. <writer><name sort="Carter, Chris">Chris Carter</name></writer> wrote the screenplay. The story is by Carter and <writer><name sort="Spotnitz, Frank">Frank Spotnitz</name></writer>. It is the first feature film based on The X-Files television series created by Carter that revolves around fictional unsolved cases called the X-Files and the characters solving them. Five main characters from the television series appear in the film: <actor><name sort="Duchovny, David">David Duchovny</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Anderson, Gillian">Gillian Anderson</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Pileggi, Mitch">Mitch Pileggi</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Neville, John">John Neville</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Davis, William B.">William B. Davis</name></actor> reprise their respective roles as FBI agents Fox Mulder and Dana Scully, FBI Assistant Director Walter Skinner, Well-Manicured Man and the Cigarette-Smoking Man. The film was promoted with the tagline Fight the Future.</p>
			<p>The film takes place between seasons five (episode "The End") and six (episode "The Beginning") of the television series, and is based upon the series' extraterrestrial mythology. The story follows agents Mulder and Scully, removed from their usual jobs on the X-Files, and investigating the bombing of a building and the destruction of criminal evidence. They uncover what appears to be a government conspiracy attempting to hide the truth about an alien colonization of Earth.</p>
			<p>Chris Carter decided to make a feature film to explore the show's mythology on a wider scale, as well as appealing to non-fans. He wrote the story with Frank Spotnitz at the end of 1996 and, with a budget from 20th Century Fox, filming began in 1997, following the end of the show's fourth season. Carter assembled cast and crew from the show, as well as some other, well-known actors such as <actor><name sort="Danner, Blythe">Blythe Danner</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Landau, Martin">Martin Landau</name></actor>, to begin production on what they termed "Project Blackwood". The film was produced by Carter and <producer><name sort="Sackheim, Daniel">Daniel Sackheim</name></producer>. Mark Snow continued his role as X-Files composer to create the film's score.</p>
			<p>The film premiered on June 19, 1998 in the United States, and received mixed to positive reviews from critics. Although some enjoyed the style and effects of the film, others found the plot confusing and viewed it as little more than an extended episode of the series. A sequel, The X-Files: I Want to Believe, was released ten years later.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
	<film>
		<title>The Year My Voice Broke</title>
		<released>1987-10-17</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Duigan, John">John Duigan</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Hayes, Terry">Terry Hayes</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Miller, George">George Miller</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Mitchell, Doug">Doug Mitchell</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>PG</rating>
		<country>Australia</country>
		<genre>Drama, Romance</genre>
		<image>theyearmyvoicebroke.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Year_My_Voice_Broke" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>The Year My Voice Broke is a 1987 coming of age drama film written and directed by <writer><name sort="Duigan, John">John Duigan</name></writer> and starring <actor><name sort="Taylor, Noah">Noah Taylor</name></actor>, <actor><name sort="Carmen, Leone">Loene Carmen</name></actor>, and <actor><name sort="Mendelsohn, Ben">Ben Mendelsohn</name></actor>.</p>
			<p>Set in 1962 in the rural Southern Tablelands of New South Wales, it was the first in a projected trilogy of films centred on the experiences of an awkward Australian boy, based on the childhood of writer/director John Duigan. Although the trilogy never came to fruition, it was followed by a sequel, Flirting. It was the recipient of the 1987 Australian Film Institute Award for Best Film.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>	
	<film>
		<title>Z</title>
		<released>1969-02-26</released>
		<director>
			<name sort="Costa-Gavras">Costa-Gavras</name>
		</director>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Perrin, Jacques">Jacques Perrin</name>
		</producer>
		<producer>
			<name sort="Rachedi, Ahmed">Ahmed Rachedi</name>
		</producer>
		<rating>M</rating>
		<country>France</country>
		<genre>Thriller</genre>
		<image>z.jpg</image>
		<link url="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Z_(1969_film)" title="Wikipedia page" />
		<summary>
			<p>Z is a 1969 Algerian French language political thriller directed by Costa-Gavras, with a screenplay by <writer><name sort="Costa-Gravas">Gavras</name></writer> and <writer><name sort="Semprum, Jorge">Jorge Semprun</name></writer>, based on the 1966 novel of the same name by Vassilis Vassilikos. The film presents a thinly fictionalized account of the events surrounding the assassination of democratic Greek politician Grigoris Lambrakis in 1963. With its satirical view of Greek politics, its dark sense of humor, and its downbeat ending, the film captures the outrage about the military dictatorship that ruled Greece at the time of its making.</p>
			<p>Z stars <actor><name sort="Trintignant, Jean-Louis">Jean-Louis Trintignant</name></actor> as the investigating magistrate (an analogue of Christos Sartzetakis). International stars <actor><name sort="Montand, Yves">Yves Montand</name></actor> and <actor><name sort="Papas, Irene">Irene Papas</name></actor> also appear, but despite their star billing have very little screen time. <actor><name sort="Perrin, Jacques">Jacques Perrin</name></actor>, who co-produced, plays a key role. The film's title refers to a popular Greek protest slogan (Greek: ?e?, IPA: ['zi]) meaning "he lives," in reference to Lambrakis.</p>
			<p>The film had a total of 3,952,913 admissions in France and was the 4th highest grossing film of the year. It was also the 12th highest grossing film of 1969 in the U.S. Z is also one of the few films to be nominated for both the Academy Award for Best Foreign Language Film and Best Picture.</p>
		</summary>
	</film>
</collection>