<?xml version="1.0"?>
<people>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Allen, Woody">Heywood "Woody" Allen</name>
		<image>002.jpg</image>
		<date type="birth">1955-12-01</date>
		<place>The Bronx, New York, USA</place>
		<p>(Born Allan Stewart Konigsberg), An American actor, comedian, filmmaker and playwright whose career spans more than 50 years.</p>
		<p>Allen has been nominated 24 times and won four Academy Awards: three for Best Original Screenplay and one for Best Director (<title>Annie Hall</title>). He has more screenwriting Academy Award nominations than any other writer, and has won nine British Academy of Film and Television Arts Awards. His screenplay for Annie Hall was named the funniest screenplay by the Writers Guild of America in its list of the "101 Funniest Screenplays."</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Keaton, Diane">Diane Keaton</name>
		<image>003.jpg</image>
		<date type="birth">1946-01-05</date>
		<place>Los Angeles, California, USA</place>
		<p>(Born Diane Hall), An American film actress, director, producer and screenwriter. She began her career on stage and made her screen debut in 1970.</p>
		<p>Her first major film role was as Kay Adams-Corleone in <title>The Godfather</title>
			<date type="released">1972</date>, but the films that shaped her early career were those with director and co-star Woody Allen, beginning with <title>Play It Again, Sam</title> in <date type="released">1972</date>. Her next two films with Allen, <title>Sleeper</title>
			<date type="released">1973</date> and <title>Love and Death</title>
			<date type="released">1975</date>, established her as a comic actor. Her fourth, <title>Annie Hall</title>
			<date type="released">1977</date>, won her the Academy Award for Best Actress.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Pryce, Jonathan">Jonathan Pryce</name>
		<image>004.jpg</image>
		<date type="birth">1947-06-01</date>
		<place>Carmel, Flintshire, Wales, UK</place>
		<p>(Born John Price), A Welsh actor and singer.</p>
		<p>After studying at the Royal Academy of Dramatic Art and meeting his longtime girlfriend, English actress Kate Fahy, in 1974, he began his career as a stage actor in the 1970s. His work in theatre, including an award-winning performance in the title role of the Royal Court Theatre's <title>Hamlet</title>, led to several supporting roles in film and television. He made his breakthrough screen performance in Terry Gilliam's <date type="released">1985</date> cult film <title>Brazil</title>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="De Niro, Robert">Robert De Niro</name>
		<image>005.jpg</image>
			<date type="birth">1943-08-17</date>
		<place>Manhattan, New York, USA</place>
		<p>An American actor and producer who has starred in over 90 films.</p>
		<p>De Niro played Michael Vronsky in the acclaimed Vietnam War film <title>The Deer Hunter</title>
			<date type="released">1978</date>, for which he was nominated for Best Actor in a Leading Role. Fearing he had become typecast in mob roles, he began expanding into occasional comedic roles in the mid-1980s and has had much success there as well, with such films as <title>Brazil</title>
			<date type="released">1985</date>, <title>Midnight Run</title>
			<date type="released">1988</date>, <title>Analyze This</title>
			<date type="released">1999</date>, <title>Meet the Parents</title>
			<date type="released">2000</date>, and <title>Meet the Fockers</title>
			<date type="released">2004</date>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Griest, Kim">Kimberley Bret "Kim" Greist</name>
		<image>006.jpg</image>
		<date type="birth">1958-05-12</date>
		<place>Stamford, Connecticut, USA</place>
		<p>An American actress.</p>
		<p>Her first film appearance was in the horror film, <title>C.H.U.D.</title>
			<date type="released">1984</date>, soon followed by a guest appearance in the <date type="released">1985</date> Miami Vice episode <title>Nobody Lives Forever</title>. Greist also appeared in a few 1980s films, including <title>Brazil</title>
			<date type="released">1985</date>, Michael Mann's <title>Manhunter</title>
			<date type="released">1986</date>, <title>Throw Momma from the Train</title>
			<date type="released">1987</date> and <title>Punchline</title>
			<date type="released">1988</date>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Palin, Michael">Michael Edward Palin</name>
		<image>007.jpg</image>
		<date type="birth">1943-05-05</date>
		<place>Broomhill, Sheffield, West Riding of Yorkshire, England</place>
		<p>An English comedian, actor, writer and television presenter.</p>
		<p>In <date type="released">1984</date>, he reunited with Terry Gilliam to appear in <title>Brazil</title>. He appeared in the comedy film <title>A Fish Called Wanda</title>, for which he won the BAFTA Award for Best Actor in a Supporting Role. Cleese reunited the main cast almost a decade later to make <title>Fierce Creatures</title>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Helmond, Katherine">Katherine Marie Helmond</name>
		<image>008.jpg</image>
		<date type="birth">1929-07-05</date>
		<place>Galveston, Texas, USA</place>
		<p>An American film, theater and television actress, voice artist and director.</p>
		<p>Helmond appeared in such feature films as <title>Family Plot</title>
			<date type="released">1976</date> and <title>Brazil</title>
			<date type="released">1985</date>, playing the mother of Jonathan Pryce's character. In 1983, she studied at the American Film Institute's Directing Workshop, and went on to direct four episodes of the television series <title>Benson</title>, as well as one episode of <title>Who's the Boss?</title>
			<date type="released">1984</date>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Hoskins, Bob">Robert William "Bob" Hoskins</name>
		<image>009.jpg</image>
		<date type="birth">1942-10-26</date>
		<date type="death">2014-04-29</date>
		<place>Bury St Edmunds, West Suffolk, England</place>
		<p>Was an English actor known for playing Cockneys and gangsters.</p>
		<p>Hoskins' performances in British films, such as <title>The Long Good Friday</title>
			<date type="released">1980</date> and <title>Mona Lisa</title>
			<date type="released">1986</date>, won him the wider approval of the critics and, in the case of the latter, a Cannes Award, Best Actor Golden Globe and BAFTA Awards, and an Academy Award nomination for Best Actor. He also delivered comic turns in Terry Gilliam's <title>Brazil</title>
			<date type="released">1985</date> and as Mario in <title>Super Mario Bros</title>
			<date type="released">1993</date>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Holm, Ian">Sir Ian Holm</name>
		<image>010.jpg</image>
			<date type="birth">1931-09-12</date>
		<place>Goodmayes, Essex, England</place>
		<p>An English actor known for his stage work and many film roles.</p>
		<p>In the 1980s, he had memorable roles in <title>Time Bandits</title>
			<date type="released">1981</date>, <title>Greystoke: The Legend of Tarzan, Lord of the Apes</title>
			<date type="released">1984</date> and Terry Gilliam's <title>Brazil</title>
			<date type="released">1985</date>. He played Lewis Carroll, author of Alice in Wonderland in the Dennis Potter-scripted fantasy <title>Dreamchild</title>
			<date type="released">1985</date>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Welles, Orson">George Orson Welles</name>
		<image>011.jpg</image>
			<date type="birth">1915-05-06</date>
			<date type="death">1985-10-10</date>
		<place>Kenosha, Wisconsin, USA</place>
		<p>Was an American actor, director, writer, and producer who worked in theatre, radio, and film.</p>
		<p>He is best remembered for his innovative work in all three: in theatre, most notably <title>Caesar</title>
			<date type="released">1937</date>, a Broadway adaptation of William Shakespeare's Julius Caesar; in radio, the <date type="released">1938</date> broadcast "<title>The War of the Worlds</title>", one of the most famous in the history of radio; and in film, <title>Citizen Kane</title>
			<date type="released">1941</date>, consistently ranked as one of the all-time greatest films.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Sellers, Peter">Peter Sellers</name>
		<image>012.jpg</image>
			<date type="birth">1925-09-08</date>
            <date type="death">1980-07-24</date>
		<place>Portsmouth, UK</place>
		<p>Was a British film actor, comedian and singer.</p>
		<p>Sellers garnered much critical acclaim for his work; he was nominated three times for an Academy Award, twice for the Academy Award for Best Actor for his performances in <title>Dr. Strangelove</title> and <title>Being There</title>, and once for the Academy Award for Best Live Action Short Film for <title>The Running Jumping &amp; Standing Still Film</title>
			<date type="released">1960</date>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Scott, George C.">George Campbell Scott</name>
		<image>013.jpg</image>
			<date type="birth">1927-10-18</date>
			<date type="death">1999-10-22</date>
		<place>Wise, Virginia, USA</place>
		<p>Was an American stage and film actor, director, and producer.</p>
		<p>He was best known for his stage work, as well as his portrayal of General George S. Patton in the film <title>Patton</title>, as General Buck Turgidson in Stanley Kubrick's <title>Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb</title>, and as Ebenezer Scrooge in Clive Donner's <date type="released">1984</date> film <title>A Christmas Carol</title>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Hayden, Sterling">Sterling Walter Hayden</name> 
		<image>014.jpg</image>
			<date type="birth">1916-03-26</date>
            <date type="death">1986-05-23</date>
		<place>Montclair, New Jersey, USA</place>
		<p>(Born Sterling Relyea), was an American actor and author.</p>
		<p>For most of his career as a leading man, he specialized in westerns and film noir, such as <title>Johnny Guitar</title>, <title>The Asphalt Jungle</title>, and <title>The Killing</title>. Later on he became noted as a character actor for such roles as Gen. Jack D. Ripper in <title>Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb</title>
			<date type="released">1964</date>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Wynn, Keenan">Keenan Wynn</name>
		<image>015.jpg</image>
			<date type="birth">1916-07-27</date>
            <date type="death">1986-10-14</date>
		<place>New York, New York, USA</place>
		<p>Was an American character actor.</p>
		<p>His early postwar credits include <title>Annie Get Your Gun</title>
			<date type="released">1950</date>, <title>Royal Wedding</title>
			<date type="released">1951</date>, <title>Kiss Me, Kate</title>
			<date type="released">1953</date>, <title>Battle Circus</title>
			<date type="released">1953</date>, <title>The Man in the Gray Flannel Suit</title>
			<date type="released">1956</date>, <title>A Hole in the Head</title>
			<date type="released">1959</date>, <title>The Absent-Minded Professor</title>
			<date type="released">1961</date>, <title>Son of Flubber</title>
			<date type="released">1963</date> and <title>Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb</title>
			<date type="released">1964</date>.</p>
	</bio>
	<bio>
		<name sort="Pickens, Slim">Louis Burton Lindley, Jr.</name>
		<image>016.jpg</image>
			<date type="birth">1919-06-29</date>
            <date type="death">"1983-12-08</date>
		<place>Kingsburg, California, USA</place>
		<p>Better known by his stage name Slim Pickens, was an American rodeo performer and film and television actor.</p>
		<p>Pickens appeared in dozens of films, including <title>Old Oklahoma Plains</title>
			<date type="released">1952</date>, <title>Down Laredo Way</title>
			<date type="released">1953</date>, <title>Tonka</title>
			<date type="released">1959</date>, <title>One-Eyed Jacks</title>
			<date type="released">1961</date> with Marlon Brando, <title>Dr. Strangelove or: How I Learned to Stop Worrying and Love the Bomb</title>
			<date type="released">1964</date>, <title>Major Dundee</title>
			<date type="released">1965</date> with Charlton Heston, the remake of <title>Stagecoach</title> (<date type="released">1966</date>; Pickens played the driver, portrayed in the <date type="released">1939</date> film by Andy Devine), <title>Never a Dull Moment</title>
			<date type="released">1968</date>, <title>The Cowboys</title>
			<date type="released">1972</date> with John Wayne, <title>Ginger in the Morning</title>
			<date type="released">1974</date> with Fred Ward, <title>Blazing Saddles</title>
			<date type="released">1974</date>, <title>Poor Pretty Eddie</title>
			<date type="released">1975</date>, <title>Rancho Deluxe</title>
			<date type="released">1975</date>, <title>The Getaway</title> with Steve McQueen, <title>Tom Horn</title>
			<date type="released">1980</date>, also with McQueen, <title>An Eye for an Eye</title>
			<date type="released">1966</date> and Pat Garrett and Billy the Kid <date type="released">1973</date> in a small but memorable role.</p>
	</bio>
</people>